ARSHDEEP SONI

17 Treadgold House, 25 Bomore Road, London, W11 4HD

■ ArshDSoni@gmail.com • ☐ 07588418134 • ☐ 02072214250

www.github.com/arshsoni • • ArshSoni.github.io

Summarv

Enthusiastic Front-End Developer with 1+ years of commercial experience and solid experience of latest technologies, exceptional flexibility as well as a keen desire to improve and develop new skills. Excellent attention to detail and a high level of accuracy regarding quality and presentation of work.

A fast learner and team player, seeking a full time job in Front End Web Development for after graduation.

Experience

Front End Developer - University Placement

June 2016 - Present

Yell.com - Reading

- Redesigned the homepage, search page, business page, header and footer for Smartphone and Desktop
- Updated user journey's for Free-listing and Connect apps for both platforms using modern techniques
- Worked within several teams and built Yell Articles (Wordpress), improving SEO using Structured Data
- Developed the Content Tool (internal tool for social profiles), with scrum master experience
- Followed agile methodology and contributed towards clean, organised and readable code with Unit Tests
- My contract was extended and I was offered a part time role whilst I complete my final year
- Technologies Used: HTML/Freemarker, ES6, SASS, JQuery, RequireJS, Grunt, Jasmine

Full-Stack Developer - Freelance

2015 - Present

- Worked alongside clients to develop modern websites as per their requirements
- www.ArshdeepSoni.com Personal Magician Website
- www.MagicSingh.com Simple website for a client supporting a blog system and a minimal shop
- www, Josh Photography, co.uk Online portfolio for a client Photographer, with a backend CMS
- www.SoniMakeovers.co.uk Website for my mother who is a Make-up Artist
- www.SJMagic.co.uk Website for a Magician with CMS to manage content

Professional Magician

2012/13 - Present

- Performed for several corporate and private events
- Very active on social media
- Improved Interpersonal, Communication and Presentation skills, huge confidence boost, a great ice breaker

Education

(BSc) in Computer Science - Royal Holloway University of London

2014 - Present

Third Year (Prediction): (First 1St) First Year: (First 1st) Second Year: (First 1st)

(A Levels) - William Morris Sixth Form: ABB in ICT, Maths and Economics respectively

2012 - 2014

Skills

- Excellent HTML & CSS Knowledge Progressive Enhancement
- Advance JS/ES6 knowledge
- Unit Testing: Mocha, Chai
- Experience with B.E.M
- Adobe Photoshop/Illustrator
- Intermediate ¡Query
- MySQL and PostgreSQL
- · Cross Browser Testing
- CMS (Wordpress)

- Excellent Responsive Design skills
- NodeJS, ExpressJS, PHP and Java
- Experience with SASS/SCSS
- Web Performance, RequireJS
- W3C Standards

Achievements

In the process of completing The Magic Cricle Exam Personal Web Development projects Currently undertaking A+ and Network+ courses provided by CompTIA

Interests and Hobbies

Performing Magic · Photography/Videography · Driving · Drone Flying · Theme Park enthusiast